<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mathco.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://mathco.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-25T21:19:28+09:00</updated><id>https://mathco.me/feed.xml</id><title type="html">mathC0.</title><subtitle>mathCo area........</subtitle><entry><title type="html">urban</title><link href="https://mathco.me/20230222/urban-heat-island" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="urban" /><published>2023-02-22T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://mathco.me/20230222/urban-heat-island</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mathco.me/20230222/urban-heat-island"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heat-island">heat island</h1>
<p><span style="font-size:11px">medium fama</span></p>

<p>The urban heat island phenomenon refers to a phenomenon in which the temperature of an area is relatively higher than that of other surrounding areas. It is named because it is thought that the isolines of the temperature distribution are in a considerable equivalence relationship with the contour lines of islands floating in the sea, and by definition it can be regarded as one of the local climates.</p>

<p>Compared to the surrounding areas, it heats up relatively quickly and cools down slowly, so the temperature difference is usually greater at night than during the day and in winter than summer, and is most noticeable when synoptic winds blow weakly, mixing heat north and south and weak confidence. The heat island phenomenon was first investigated and described by Luke Howard in the late 1810s.</p>

<p>heat island phenomenon can be obtained when the atmospheric radiological approach is taken.</p>

<p>When applying the concept of blackbody radiation to the Earth, Since the ratio of the absorptance and the reflectance of an object to radiation of the same wavelength at a constant temperature in thermodynamically thermal equilibrium must have a constant value regardless of the nature of the object, Planck, Stefan - Boltzman Law, E (energy) is absorbed, it must emit an equivalent value.</p>

<p>According to the Stefan - Boltzman law, the total radiant flux of an object emitted by a blackbody is proportional to the fourth power of the absolute temperature (K). Therefore, a greenhouse effect of 33 degrees is generated by the atmosphere.</p>

<p>In addition, according to Kirchhoff’s radiation law, when the wavelength and temperature are constant, the absorptivity and emissivity of a material are equivalent. The more radiation an object absorbs, the more it emits.</p>

<p>Albedo is used to describe the reflectivity of an object. A white object has a high light reflectance due to a large Albedo, and a black object has a small Albedo due to a higher absorption than light reflectance.</p>

<p>First, there is the light trapping phenomenon. Buildings in cities are dominated by gray, have fewer objects that can be reflected by using a lot of glass, and have a small albedo due to high absorption. On the other hand, the suburbs are dominated by trees, and have a high Albedo because they reflect a lot of shortwave radiation because they are green and yellow.</p>

<p>Buildings in the city center are not uniform in height, so there are vertical buildings and shadows between them. At this time, when light enters, reflection between buildings occurs and it is trapped inside the building in a Z shape, and in this process, the building absorbs solar shortwave radiation.</p>

<p>Kirchhoff’s radiation law, when the wavelength and temperature are constant, the absorptance and emissivity of a material are equivalent, so the heat absorbed by the city during the daytime emits a relatively larger heat radiation flux than the suburbs at night, resulting in a temperature higher than that of the suburbs.</p>

<li><strong><span style="font-size:16px">References</span></strong></li>
<p></p>

<ol>
	<li><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">&nbsp; The climate of London, deduced from Meteorological observations, made at different places in the neighborhood of the metropolis (Howard, 1818-20)</span></li>
	<li><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">&nbsp; An approach to heat island according to the law of Kirchhoff&#39;s (Weather Center of Seoul, 2019)</span></li>
	<li><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">&nbsp;The energetic basis of the urban heat island(Oke, 1982)</span></li>
	<li><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">&nbsp; LANDSAT image used Sejong Special Self-Governing City urbanization and heat island effect Analysis (Kim, 2014)</span></li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="A" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[heat island medium fama]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">modern art</title><link href="https://mathco.me/20230220/contemporary-art" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="modern art" /><published>2023-02-20T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-02-20T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://mathco.me/20230220/contemporary-art</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mathco.me/20230220/contemporary-art"><![CDATA[<h1 id="contemporary-art---minimalist-phenomenon">contemporary art - minimalist phenomenon</h1>
<p><span style="font-size:11px">sensitivo articulum</span></p>

<p><span style="color:#000000">The rise of minimalism, or minimalism, is thought to have occurred in the 1960s. Minimalist artists such as Carl Andre and Frank Stella are said to have been the first to display simple boxes or metal plates in the exhibition space.<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1" title="">[1]</a></span></p>

<p><span style="color:#000000">Abstract Expressionism focused on &#39;flatness&#39; and &#39;visibility&#39; as conditions for painting, reflecting the idea that each field such as literature, painting, sculpture, music, theater, and architecture has its own characteristics and should be focused on them. If a logic that can protect the purity of the medium, such as architecture that focuses on the volume of space or music that focuses on sound and the passage of time, is applied, the logic of abstract expressionist artists can be seen as that the painting is on a &quot;plane.&quot; Because they see painting as &quot;dramatic&quot; and landscape as &quot;architectural&quot; (three-dimensional), they prefer random abstract representations rather than figures and landscapes.<a href="#_ftn2" name="_ftnref2" title="">[2]</a></span></p>

<p><span style="color:#000000">In defiance of these strict principles, minimalism denies flatness and has its origins in the attempt to make it appear theatrical or architectural in a deliberate&nbsp;reverse.<a href="#_ftn3" name="_ftnref3" title="">[3]</a>&nbsp; It showed works such as drawing lines inside the canvas along the shape of the canvas, placing flat boxes one after another in the exhibition space, or hanging objects such as boxes on the wall. It tried to criticize the Abstract Expressionists by claiming that this was a &quot;painting&quot; and revealing that the painting had a &quot;thickness&quot; like a sculpture and therefore could not be flattened in the first place.<a href="#_ftn4" name="_ftnref4" title="">[4]</a></span></p>

<p><span style="color:#000000">In the process, minimalist artists embraced Husserl&#39;s phenomenology. Phenomenology is the study of expressing only the &quot;phenomenon&quot; felt in the &quot;now&quot; and &quot;here&quot;, and minimalist artists placed simple objects in the exhibition space simply to examine the phenomenon of the object felt in the &quot;now&quot; and &quot;here&quot;. </span></p>

<li><strong><span style="font-size:16px">Development</span></strong></li>
<p></p>

<p><span style="color:#000000">These concepts, such as the perception of time and space, the importance of a particular place, and the feeling of a relationship, have had a great influence on the contemporary art world since then. In pursuit of its influence, conceptual art began by asserting the necessity of artistic perception of &#39;concepts&#39;, which are the output of cognitive processes across space and time.<a href="#_ftn5" name="_ftnref5" title="">[5]</a>&nbsp; Earth art began with the idea of aiming for outdoor activities in order to be free from the constraints of a fixed &quot;place&quot; within an art museum. The installation art began with the idea that &quot;unlike existing sculptures, whose meaning does not change even if they are moved to another place, why not try &#39;site-specific&#39; art that is meaningful only in &#39;place&#39;?&quot; The work of criticizing the system began with the thought, &quot;Then, wouldn&#39;t it be possible to criticize the system in a place dominated by a typical art system, such as an art museum?&quot; Finally, the work of relational aesthetics asks, &quot;Isn&#39;t it possible to artistically sublimate the relationship between people and communities?&quot;<a href="#_ftn6" name="_ftnref6" title="">[6]</a></span></p>

<p><span style="color:#000000">This minimalism began to influence not only the Western art world, but also other regions. For example, minimalism influenced other disciplines, such as design and architecture.</span></p>

<li><strong><span style="font-size:16px">Result</span></strong></li>
<p></p>

<p><span style="color:#000000">The acceleration of globalization has been in a transitional period with an emphasis on server sharing on the network, and obstacles come into play: the advent of smartphones has increased the accessibility of international networks. Thus, the longitudinal user design has been simplified, which is believed to be the root that led to the misinterpretation of minimalism.<a href="#_ftn7" name="_ftnref7" title="">[7]</a>&nbsp;The popularity of the field is sufficient to believe that this closed culture has led to its &quot;spread&quot; to the modern art world.</span></p>

<p><span style="color:#000000">Judging from the history of minimalism, it is thought that minimalism is a movement to imply only the meaning that should be emphasized, and that excessive abstraction may not be generally appropriate for its purpose.</span></p>

<li><strong><span style="font-size:16px">References</span></strong></li>
<p></p>

<p><span style="color:#000000">References (citations) format: &nbsp;APA 6 <sup>th</sup> &ndash; for both taste notes and standard APA forms.</span></p>

<p><span style="color:#000000">DOI notation : Early (ancient) notation format.</span></p>

<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif"><a href="applewebdata://CB63A60E-6857-44A0-86DE-199830DCEA05#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1" title="">[1]</a> <em>Minimalist novel</em> (Kim Sung-gon, 1994)</span></p>

<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif"><a href="applewebdata://CB63A60E-6857-44A0-86DE-199830DCEA05#_ftnref2" name="_ftn2" title="">[2]</a> Strickland, E. (1993). <em>Minimalism: Origins Indiana University Press.</em></span></p>

<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif"><a href="applewebdata://CB63A60E-6857-44A0-86DE-199830DCEA05#_ftnref3" name="_ftn3" title="">[3]</a> <em>I</em><em>ndiana university press -- minimalism</em>: Origins by edward strickland / sourcebook for research in music by phillip D. crabtree and donald H. foster / expressionism in twentieth-century music by john C. crawford and dorothy L. crawford / and others. (1994).&nbsp;The American Music Teacher,&nbsp;44(1), 40.</span></p>

<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif"><a href="applewebdata://CB63A60E-6857-44A0-86DE-199830DCEA05#_ftnref4" name="_ftn4" title=""><em>[4]</em></a><em> Berstel, J., &amp; Reutenauer, C.</em> (2010). Minimization. In&nbsp;Noncommutative Rational Series with Applications&nbsp;(Encyclopedia of Mathematics and its Applications, pp. 29-46). Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. doi:10.1017/CBO9780511760860.003</span></p>

<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif"><a href="applewebdata://CB63A60E-6857-44A0-86DE-199830DCEA05#_ftnref5" name="_ftn5" title="">[5]</a> Best, S. (2006). <em>Minimalism, subjectivity, and aesthetics: Rethinking the anti-aesthetic tradition in late-modern art</em>.<em>&nbsp;</em><em>Journal of Visual Art Practice,</em><em>&nbsp;</em><em>5</em>(3), 127. doi:10.1386/jvap.5.3.127_1</span></p>

<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif"><a href="applewebdata://CB63A60E-6857-44A0-86DE-199830DCEA05#_ftnref6" name="_ftn6" title="">[6]</a> <em>Consolidated authors, references omitted</em></span></p>

<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif"><a href="applewebdata://CB63A60E-6857-44A0-86DE-199830DCEA05#_ftnref7" name="_ftn7" title="">[7]</a> Rutter, B. (2010). The problem of a modern art. In&nbsp;<em>Hegel on the Modern Arts</em>&nbsp;(Modern European Philosophy, pp. 6-62). Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. doi:10.1017/CBO9780511760440.002</span></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="A" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[contemporary art - minimalist phenomenon sensitivo articulum]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dmitri Mendeleev</title><link href="https://mathco.me/20230219/dmitri-mendeleev" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dmitri Mendeleev" /><published>2023-02-19T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://mathco.me/20230219/dmitri-mendeleev</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mathco.me/20230219/dmitri-mendeleev"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<center><img width="200" alt="Math" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/c8/DIMendeleevCab.jpg/1024px-DIMendeleevCab.jpg" /></center>
<h1 style="text-align:center">Dmitri Mendeleev</h1>

<h1 id="1869"><a name="Lists"></a>1869</h1>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Cl 35.5</td>
      <td>K 39</td>
      <td>Ca 40</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Br 80</td>
      <td>Rb 85</td>
      <td>Sr 88</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>I 127</td>
      <td>Cs 133</td>
      <td>Ba 137</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="B" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dmitri Mendeleev]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">atom observing</title><link href="https://mathco.me/20230117/stm" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="atom observing" /><published>2023-01-17T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://mathco.me/20230117/stm</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mathco.me/20230117/stm"><![CDATA[<h1 id="observation-of-atomic-level-objects">Observation of Atomic-Level Objects</h1>
<p><span style="font-size:11px">fama</span></p>

<p>Assuming that a voltage is applied between a metal probe with a sharp end and the surface of a conductor or semiconductor sample, if the distance between the probe and the sample becomes very close and converges, current flows in a non-contact state due to the quantum mechanical tunneling effect. In this situation, when the change in the distance between the probe and the sample surface is not zero on an atomic scale, the change in the magnitude of the current occurs within a small error range. By this principle, the distribution of atoms can be grasped, and thus atomic-level objects can be observed. This observer is called the Scanning Tunneling Microscope (STM).</p>

<li><strong><span style="font-size:16px">Quantum Mechanical Tunneling of Electrons</span></strong></li>
<p></p>

<p>In classical mechanics, particles cannot cross a higher energy barrier than they have. The nucleons constituting the nucleus are strongly bound together by the action of the nuclear force. This is referred to as a potential barrier. According to classical mechanics, it is impossible for a nucleon to escape out of an atom because it has less energy than the potential barrier creates. However, in reality, alpha particles in radioactive materials leave the nucleus with less energy than the nuclear force, and this is called the tunnel effect (quantum mechanical tunneling).</p>

<p>This allows electrons to move from one side to the other through the energy barrier of the vacuum by applying a bias voltage between the tip and the sample while the conductive tip is very close to the sample surface in the STM. To observe the surface, the tunneling current flowing between the tip and the sample is observed on the sample surface at the tip end, where the resulting tunneling current is determined by the location of the tip, the applied voltage, and the sample’s local state density (LODS).</p>

<li><strong><span style="font-size:16px">Required degree of vacuum</span></strong></li>
<p></p>

<p>Gas molecules continuously move due to interference, and there is a very high probability of causing interference by affecting collisions due to high density and randomness. As a specific cause of interference in the STM, observation of the sample surface is hindered by attaching to the surface of the sample to be observed, reacting with the surface, or covering the surface. In experiments using STM for easy observation, it is necessary to block contact between the sample to be observed and gas molecules as much as possible, so a vacuum state is ideal.</p>

<p>Vacuum refers to a state in which gas pressure is lower than atmospheric pressure, and gas pressure and vacuum are inversely proportional. When the temperature inside the vacuum cylinder is constant and only one type of gas molecules exist, the gas pressure inside the cylinder is proportional to the number of gas molecules floating around per unit volume, regardless of the type of gas molecules. Therefore, the gas pressure inside the vacuum canister can be lowered by extracting the gas molecules from the vacuum canister or immobilizing them inside the vacuum canister.</p>

<p>The time it takes for gas molecules floating inside the vacuum tank to attach to the surface of the sample to be observed and form a film is called the monomolecular layer formation time. The higher the collision frequency of gas molecules per unit area, the shorter it is. In addition, according to gas kinetic theory, at a fixed temperature, the larger the mass of gas molecules or the lower the pressure of the gas, the longer the monomolecular layer formation time.</p>

<p>In the case of nitrogen, the monomolecular layer formation time is 3 × 10 -9 seconds at 20 ° C and 760 Torr atmospheric pressure, but increases to approximately 2,500 seconds when the pressure is reduced to 10 -9 Torr on the same temperature line. For this reason, it can be obtained that a scanning tunneling microscope usually requires an ultra-high vacuum state of 10 −9 Torr or less in order to secure an observable time of the sample.</p>

<li><strong><span style="font-size:16px">Ion pump</span></strong></li>
<p></p>

<p>In order to practically implement ultra-high vacuum, an ion pump is generally used. The ion pump is composed of a permanent magnet, a cylindrical anode made of metal, and a cathode in the form of a plate made of titanium. A magnetic field induced by a magnet is hung in the axial direction of the cylindrical anode, and a high voltage of 2 to 7 kV is applied between the anode and cathode.</p>

<p>Under the influence of the high voltage applied between the anode and the cathode, the electrons emitted from the cathode move to the anode while drawing a complex trajectory under the influence of the magnetic field. In this process, the electrons emitted from the cathode collide with the surrounding gas molecules and separate the gas molecules into their components, positive ions and electrons. Here, the magnetic field increases the distance electrons travel to the anode compared to when there is no magnetic field, thereby increasing the frequency of collisions between electrons and gas molecules. Positive ions generated in this process are pulled to the cathode by the electric force and become embedded in the cathode, making them unable to move. This is called the primary pumping action.</p>

<p>When the positive ions hit the cathode, the titanium breaks off and sticks around the impact point. Due to its high chemical reactivity, the attached titanium easily reacts with various gas molecules and adsorbs the floating gas molecules. Since this has the effect of reducing the number of floating gas molecules, this is called secondary pumping.
Therefore, an ultra-high vacuum state can be created by the action of the first and second ion pumps.</p>

<li><strong><span style="font-size:16px">Origins and References</span></strong></li>
<p></p>

<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">Origin: September (Mock)<br />
et cetera:</span></p>

<ol>
	<li><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">June 2012 (Mock Test) &ndash; History and types of vacuum tubes (1/2)</span></li>
	<li><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">&ldquo;STM References - Annotated Links for Scanning Tunneling Microscope Amateurs&rdquo;.</span></li>
	<li><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">US4,343,993　Priority number(s): CH19790008486 19790920.</span></li>
	<li><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">Jayong Koo, Dalhyun Kim. (1992). Measuring principle and application of scanning tunneling microscope. Journal of the Korean Society of Mechanical Engineers, 32(5), 420-428.</span></li>
	<li><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">C. Julian Chen (1993). 《Introduction to Scanning Tunneling Microscopy》 (PDF). Oxford University Press. ISBN 0-19-507150-6.</span></li>
	<li><span style="font-family:Times New Roman,Times,serif">September 2007 (Mock) &ndash; Introduction to Photography (All)</span></li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="A" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Atomic-Level Objects fama]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">good and evil</title><link href="https://mathco.me/19650615/lorem-ipsum" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="good and evil" /><published>1965-06-15T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>1965-06-15T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://mathco.me/19650615/lorem-ipsum</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mathco.me/19650615/lorem-ipsum"><![CDATA[<h1 id="de-finibus-bonorum-et-malorum">de Finibus Bonorum et Malorum</h1>
<p><span style="font-size:11px">Cicero</span></p>

<p>Sed ut perspiciatis unde omnis iste natus error sit voluptatem accusantium doloremque laudantium, totam rem aperiam, eaque ipsa quae ab illo inventore veritatis et quasi architecto beatae vitae dicta sunt explicabo. Nemo enim ipsam voluptatem quia voluptas sit aspernatur aut odit aut fugit, sed quia consequuntur magni dolores eos qui ratione voluptatem sequi nesciunt. Neque porro quisquam est, qui dolorem ipsum quia dolor sit amet, consectetur, adipisci velit, sed quia non numquam eius modi tempora incidunt ut labore et dolore magnam aliquam quaerat voluptatem. Ut enim ad minima veniam, quis nostrum exercitationem ullam corporis suscipit laboriosam, nisi ut aliquid ex ea commodi consequatur? Quis autem vel eum iure reprehenderit qui in ea voluptate velit esse quam nihil molestiae consequatur, vel illum qui dolorem eum fugiat quo voluptas nulla pariatur?</p>

<p>At vero eos et accusamus et iusto odio dignissimos ducimus qui blanditiis praesentium voluptatum deleniti atque corrupti quos dolores et quas molestias excepturi sint occaecati cupiditate non provident, similique sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollitia animi, id est laborum et dolorum fuga. Et harum quidem rerum facilis est et expedita distinctio. Nam libero tempore, cum soluta nobis est eligendi optio cumque nihil impedit quo minus id quod maxime placeat facere possimus, omnis voluptas assumenda est, omnis dolor repellendus. Temporibus autem quibusdam et aut officiis debitis aut rerum necessitatibus saepe eveniet ut et voluptates repudiandae sint et molestiae non recusandae. Itaque earum rerum hic tenetur a sapiente delectus, ut aut reiciendis voluptatibus maiores alias consequatur aut perferendis doloribus asperiores repellat.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="A" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[de Finibus Bonorum et Malorum Cicero]]></summary></entry></feed>